import { Lesson } from "../interfaces/Lesson";

export const russianVocab: Lesson[] = [
    {
      id: 1,
      question: 'И',
      romanized: 'I',
      answer: ['And']
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question: 'В (Во)',
      romanized: 'Vo',
      answer: ['In', 'Into', 'To']
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question: 'Не',
      romanized: 'Ne',
      answer: ['Not']
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question: 'На',
      romanized: 'Na',
      answer: ['On', 'At', 'To']
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question: 'Я',
      romanized: 'Ya',
      answer: ['I']
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question: 'Он',
      romanized: 'On',
      answer: ['He', 'It']
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question: 'Что',
      romanized: 'Shto',
      answer: ['What', 'That']
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: 'С (со)',
      romanized: 'S (so)',
      answer: ['With', 'From']
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question: 'Это',
      romanized: 'Eto',
      answer: ['This is', 'That is']
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question: 'Быть',
      romanized: 'Byt',
      answer: ['To be', 'There is', 'There are']
    },
    {
      id: 11,
      question: 'А',
      romanized: 'A',
      answer: ['And', 'But']
    },
    {
      id: 12,
      question: 'Весь',
      romanized: 'Ves',
      answer: ['All']
    },
    {
      id: 13,
      question: 'Они',
      romanized: 'Oni',
      answer: ['They']
    },
    {
      id: 14,
      question: 'Она',
      romanized: 'Ona',
      answer: ['She']
    },
    {
      id: 15,
      question: 'Как',
      romanized: 'Kak',
      answer: ['How', 'As', 'Like']
    },
    {
      id: 16,
      question: 'Мы',
      romanized: 'My',
      answer: ['We']
    },
    {
      id: 17,
      question: 'К (Ко)',
      romanized: 'K (Ko)',
      answer: ['Towards']
    },
    {
      id: 18,
      question: 'У',
      romanized: 'U',
      answer: ['By', 'At']
    },
    {
      id: 19,
      question: 'Вы',
      romanized: 'Vy',
      answer: ['You']
    },
    {
      id: 20,
      question: 'Этот (Эта, Это, Эти)',
      romanized: 'Etot (Eta, Eto, Eti)',
      answer: ['This']
    },
    {
      id: 21,
      question: 'За',
      romanized: 'Za',
      answer: ['For', 'Behind']
    },
    {
      id: 22,
      question: 'Тот (та, то, те)',
      romanized: 'Tot (ta, to, te)',
      answer: ['That']
    },
    {
      id: 23,
      question: 'Но',
      romanized: 'No',
      answer: ['But']
    },
    {
      id: 24,
      question: 'Ты',
      romanized: 'Ty',
      answer: ['You']
    },
    {
      id: 25,
      question: 'По',
      romanized: 'Po',
      answer: ['Along', 'Around', 'According to']
    },
    {
      id: 26,
      question: 'Из',
      romanized: 'Iz',
      answer: ['Out of', 'From']
    },
    {
      id: 27,
      question: 'О (об, обо)',
      romanized: 'O (ob, obo)',
      answer: ['About']
    },
    {
      id: 28,
      question: 'Свой',
      romanized: 'Svoi',
      answer: ['One\'s own']
    },
    {
      id: 29,
      question: 'Так',
      romanized: 'Tak',
      answer: ['So']
    },
    {
      id: 30,
      question: 'Один (Одна, Одно)',
      romanized: 'Odin (Odna, Odno)',
      answer: ['One']
    },
    {
      id: 31,
      question: 'Вот',
      romanized: 'Vot',
      answer: ['Here', 'There']
    },
    {
      id: 32,
      question: 'Который',
      romanized: 'Kotoryi',
      answer: ['Which']
    },
    {
      id: 33,
      question: 'Наш',
      romanized: 'Nash',
      answer: ['Our']
    },
    {
      id: 34,
      question: 'Только',
      romanized: 'Tolko',
      answer: ['Only']
    },
    {
      id: 35,
      question: 'Ешё',
      romanized: 'Yeshyo',
      answer: ['Still', 'Yet']
    },
    {
      id: 36,
      question: 'От',
      romanized: 'Ot',
      answer: ['From']
    },
    {
      id: 37,
      question: 'Такой',
      romanized: 'Takoy',
      answer: ['Such']
    },
    {
      id: 38,
      question: 'Мочь',
      romanized: 'Moch',
      answer: ['To be able', 'be able to', 'to be able to']
    },
    {
      id: 39,
      question: 'Говорить',
      romanized: 'Govorit',
      answer: ['Speak']
    },
    {
      id: 40,
      question: 'Сказать',
      romanized: 'Skazat',
      answer: ['Say']
    },
    {
      id: 41,
      question: 'Для',
      romanized: 'Dlya',
      answer: ['For']
    },
    {
      id: 42,
      question: 'Уже',
      romanized: 'Uzhe',
      answer: ['Already']
    },
    {
      id: 43,
      question: 'Знать',
      romanized: 'Znat',
      answer: ['Know']
    },
    {
      id: 44,
      question: 'Да',
      romanized: 'Da',
      answer: ['Yes']
    },
    {
      id: 45,
      question: 'Какой',
      romanized: 'Kakoy',
      answer: ['What kind of']
    },
    {
      id: 46,
      question: 'Когда',
      romanized: 'Kogda',
      answer: ['When']
    },
    {
      id: 47,
      question: 'Другой',
      romanized: 'Drugoy',
      answer: ['Different', 'Other']
    },
    {
      id: 48,
      question: 'Первый',
      romanized: 'Pervy',
      answer: ['First']
    },
    {
      id: 49,
      question: 'Чтобы',
      romanized: 'Chtoby',
      answer: ['In order to']
    },
    {
      id: 50,
      question: 'Его',
      romanized: 'Ego',
      answer: ['His']
    },
    {
      id: 51,
      question: 'Год',
      romanized: 'God',
      answer: ['Year']
    },
    {
      id: 52,
      question: 'Кто',
      romanized: 'Kto',
      answer: ['Who']
    },
    {
      id: 53,
      question: 'Дело',
      romanized: 'Delo',
      answer: ['Matter', 'Business']
    },
    {
      id: 54,
      question: 'Нет',
      romanized: 'Net',
      answer: ['No']
    },
    {
      id: 55,
      question: 'Её',
      romanized: 'Yeyo',
      answer: ['Her']
    },
    {
      id: 56,
      question: 'Очень',
      romanized: 'Ochen',
      answer: ['Very']
    },
    {
      id: 57,
      question: 'Большой',
      romanized: 'Bolshoy',
      answer: ['Large']
    },
    {
      id: 58,
      question: 'Новый',
      romanized: 'Novy',
      answer: ['New']
    },
    {
      id: 59,
      question: 'Стать',
      romanized: 'Stat',
      answer: ['Begin']
    },
    {
      id: 60,
      question: 'Работа',
      romanized: 'Rabota',
      answer: ['Work']
    },
    {
      id: 61,
      question: 'Сейчас',
      romanized: 'Seichas',
      answer: ['Now']
    },
    {
      id: 62,
      question: 'Время',
      romanized: 'Vremya',
      answer: ['Time']
    },
    {
      id: 63,
      question: 'Человек',
      romanized: 'Chelovek',
      answer: ['Person']
    },
    {
      id: 64,
      question: 'Идти',
      romanized: 'Idti',
      answer: ['Go', 'to go']
    },
    {
      id: 65,
      question: 'Если',
      romanized: 'Esli',
      answer: ['If']
    },
    {
      id: 66,
      question: 'Два (Две)',
      romanized: 'Dva (Dve)',
      answer: ['Two']
    },
    {
      id: 67,
      question: 'Мой',
      romanized: 'Moy',
      answer: ['My']
    },
    {
      id: 68,
      question: 'Жизнь',
      romanized: 'Zhizn',
      answer: ['Life']
    },
    {
      id: 69,
      question: 'До',
      romanized: 'Do',
      answer: ['Until']
    },
    {
      id: 70,
      question: 'Где',
      romanized: 'Gde',
      answer: ['Where']
    },
    {
      id: 71,
      question: 'Каждый',
      romanized: 'Kazhdyy',
      answer: ['Every', 'Each']
    },
    {
      id: 72,
      question: 'Самый',
      romanized: 'Samyy',
      answer: ['Most']
    },
    {
      id: 73,
      question: 'Хотеть',
      romanized: 'Hotet',
      answer: ['Want']
    },
    {
      id: 74,
      question: 'Здесь',
      romanized: 'Zdes',
      answer: ['Here']
    },
    {
      id: 75,
      question: 'Надо',
      romanized: 'Nado',
      answer: ['Must', 'Necessary', "Need to"]
    },
    {
      id: 76,
      question: 'Люди',
      romanized: 'Lyudi',
      answer: ['People']
    },
    {
      id: 77,
      question: 'Теперь',
      romanized: 'Teper',
      answer: ['Now']
    },
    {
      id: 78,
      question: 'Дом',
      romanized: 'Dom',
      answer: ['House']
    },
    {
      id: 79,
      question: 'Пойти',
      romanized: 'Poyti',
      answer: ['Go']
    },
    {
      id: 80,
      question: 'Раз',
      romanized: 'Raz',
      answer: ['Once', 'Times']
    },
    {
      id: 81,
      question: 'День',
      romanized: 'Den',
      answer: ['Day']
    },
    {
      id: 82,
      question: 'Или',
      romanized: 'Ili',
      answer: ['Or']
    },
    {
      id: 83,
      question: 'Работать',
      romanized: 'Rabotat',
      answer: ['Work']
    },
    {
      id: 84,
      question: 'Город',
      romanized: 'Gorod',
      answer: ['Town', 'City']
    },
    {
      id: 85,
      question: 'Там',
      romanized: 'Tam',
      answer: ['There']
    },
    {
      id: 86,
      question: 'Слово',
      romanized: 'Slovo',
      answer: ['Word']
    },
    {
      id: 87,
      question: 'Глаз',
      romanized: 'Glaz',
      answer: ['Eye']
    },
    {
      id: 88,
      question: 'Потом',
      romanized: 'Potom',
      answer: ['Then', 'Next']
    },
    {
      id: 89,
      question: 'Видеть',
      romanized: 'Videt',
      answer: ['See']
    },
    {
      id: 90,
      question: 'Их',
      romanized: 'Ikh',
      answer: ['Their']
    },
    {
      id: 91,
      question: 'Под',
      romanized: 'Pod',
      answer: ['Under']
    },
    {
      id: 92,
      question: 'Даже',
      romanized: 'Dazhe',
      answer: ['Even']
    },
    {
      id: 93,
      question: 'Думать',
      romanized: 'Dumat',
      answer: ['Think']
    },
    {
      id: 94,
      question: 'Хорошо',
      romanized: 'Khorosho',
      answer: ['Good', 'Well']
    },
    {
      id: 95,
      question: 'Можно',
      romanized: 'Mozhno',
      answer: ['It is possible', "possible to"]
    },
    {
      id: 96,
      question: 'Тут',
      romanized: 'Tut',
      answer: ['Here']
    },
    {
      id: 97,
      question: 'Тысяча',
      romanized: 'Tysyacha',
      answer: ['Thousand']
    },
    {
      id: 98,
      question: 'Ли',
      romanized: 'Li',
      answer: ['Whether']
    },
    {
      id: 99,
      question: 'Вода',
      romanized: 'Voda',
      answer: ['Water']
    },
    {
      id: 100,
      question: 'Ничто (Ничего)',
      romanized: 'Nichto (Nichego)',
      answer: ['Nothing']
    }
  ];
  